#### **CONTACT**

Aaron Dishy 78 Grace St. Toronto, ON, M6J 2S2 514-266-6428 hello@aarondishy.net

#### **BIO**

Aaron Dishy is an archivist and information policy researcher based in Toronto, Canada. They hold a Bachelor of Arts in communications from McGill University (2016), and a Master of Information in critical information policy studies, and archives and records management, from the University of Toronto (2018). Aaron's work centers on new media policy, archives and records management, and the implementation of information and communication technologies. The preservation and accessibility of information ground their archival practice.

### **EDUCATION**

Master of Information (M.I) Critical Information Policy Studies Archives & Records Management University of Toronto (2016 - 2018)

Bachelor of Arts (B.A) (with distinction) Communications & Art History McGill University (2012 - 2016)

Bachelor of Arts University of Copenhagen (2015)

#### **SKILLS**

Research & Publishing: academic & archival research, copy-editing, data visualization, grant writing, information collection & analysis, photoshop & layout design (Adobe Creative Suite).

Archival: archival description software, digital emulation tools, digital forensics software (BitCurator, Forensic ToolKit), disk imaging techniques, metadata schema, preservation software (Access to Memory, Archivematica, Fedora), standards (PREMIS). Experience with XML and related technologies.

Copyright: Copyright Act of Canada, Creative Commons licensing, fair dealings policy, intellectual property policy, public domain regulations, copyright registration, and open access resource tools.

Conservation: Biodeterioration reduction, basic care for books and paper artifacts, collections care, conservation science, degradation of materials care, disaster planning, mass deacidification, painting & polychrome care, photo-restoration and reprographics.

# **LANGUAGES**

English (Fluent) Hebrew/עברית (Fluent) French/Français (Reading)

#### **FELLOWSHIPS & AWARDS**

Ontario Graduate Scholarship (2016-2017)

SGS Conference Grant (2017)

McGill Merit Scholarship (2012-2014)

#### TECHNICAL PUBLICATIONS

Dishy, Aaron M.Swallowing Misandry: A Survey of the Discursive Strategies of r/TheRedPill on Reddit. Vol. 1, Flaccid Press, December 2019 (Expected).

Dishy, Aaron M. "Selfies, Sexts, and Squadrons: The Digital Culture of the Israeli Defense Forces." Journal, vol. 2, no. 3, 2017. University of Toronto, theijournal.ca/index.php/ijournal/article/view/28122.

Dishy, Aaron M. "r/Askgaybros: PrEP Participation and Health Information Dissemination on Reddit." IJournal, vol. 2, no. 3, 2018, theijournal.ca/index.php/ijournal/article/view/29495.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Studio Archivist & Assistant
John Greyson & Stephen Andrews Studio

10.2018 — Present

Acting as the studio archivist and assistant for artist Stephen Andrews and filmmaker John Greyson. This includes the production and maintenance of a functioning art archive including both analog and born-digital materials

Research Fellow 09 2017- 09 2018

University of Toronto - Patrick Keilty

Research fellow under Dr. Patrick Keilty. This research centered on analyzing and presenting data about online databases, social media studies, and contemporary archives.

Archives Assistant & Researcher

05 - 09.2017

Law Society of Ontario, Toronto

Acted as a multi-media digitization assistant, developer of records retention schedules, managed confidential information workflow, and lead legal research initiatives.

Digital Archivist 05 — 09.2016

Federation CJA, Montreal

Responsible for a community based exhibition, titled Juif d'Ici. Required archival knowledge, skill in digital curation, and understanding of preservation software.

Archives Intern 09.2015 — 06.2016

Centre for Oral History and Digital Storytelling, Montreal

Assisted in the digitization of the Montreal Life Stories Project, and maintenance of the COHDS Archive under archivist Kristen Young.

Preservation Intern 05.2015 — 01.2016

Canadian Jewish Archives, Montreal

Responsible for researching and digitizing new materials and exhibits throughout the Canadian Jewish Archives.

Research Fellow 05.2014 — 10.2015

Museum of Jewish Montreal, Montreal

Responsible for carrying out archival research about Montreal's Jewish Communities, to expand the Museum's virtual exhibition database.

Archives Assistant & Researcher

05 - 09.2014

Solnik & Solnik Office of Law, Toronto

Responsible for acquiring, drafting and digitizing legal documents. This included the production of records retention schedules, and key preservation models.

#### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

Archivist 2017-2019

Canadian Lesbian and Gay Archives

Digital Archivist
Studio XX

Layout Design
Folio Magazine

2015-2016

#### **LECTURES**

Dishy, Aaron. "Discourse, Participatory Communities and Radical Misogyny: Conceptualizing r/TheRedPill on Reddit". Thesis Lecture, moderated by Dr. Patrick Keilty, Dr. Alessandro Delfanti and Dr. Michelle Murphy. iSchool at the University of Toronto. Toronto, ON. 27 August 2018.

Dishy, Aaron. "r/askgaybros: PrEP Participation and Health Information Dissemination on Reddit". iJournal Spring Lecture Series. iSchool at the University of Toronto. Toronto, ON. 7 April 2018.

Dishy, Aaron. "Connecting the Coast: A Toolkit for User-Generated Content". Symposium in Information Policy, Regulation & Law - Moderated by Dr. Leslie Regan Shade. iSchool at the University of Toronto. Toronto, ON. 21 February 2018.

Boutchma, Marta & Dishy, Aaron. "Digital Preservation and Canadian E-Poetry: Emerging Models for Format Emulation". Lecture Series in Sensitive Cultural Content and E-Lit Preservation, directed by Dr. Christophe Becker. iSchool at the University of Toronto. Toronto, ON. 17 November 2017.

Boutchma, Marta & Dishy, Aaron. "Digital Preservation and Canadian E-Poetry: Emerging Models for Format Emulation". Lecture Series in Sensitive Cultural Content and E-Lit Preservation, directed by Dr. Christophe Becker. iSchool at the University of Toronto. Toronto, ON. 17 November 2017.

Dishy, Aaron. "Selfies, Sexts, and Squadrons: The Digital Culture of the Israeli Defense Forces". iJournal Spring Lecture Series. iSchool at the University of Toronto. Toronto, ON. 28 March 2017.

Caspary, Kaelan; Dishy, Aaron; Johnson, Amara; Wang, Junyu. "Looking Ahead at Canadian Information and Communication Policy". Future Thinking in Canada, directed by Dr. Chun Wei Choo. iSchool at the University of Toronto. Toronto, ON. 4 April 2017.

Dhar, Natasha; Dishy, Aaron; Maxine, Lauren; Rankin, Hallie; Sidhu Rajin. "The Library as Conversation: The Information Professional as Facilitator of Conversation". A Knowledge Symposium directed by Dr. Stephen Abrams. iSchool at the University of Toronto. Toronto, ON. 16 February 2017.

Dishy, Aaron & Segal, Gabrielle. "Archives, Pilgrimage and the Romanesque: Information Dissemination from Rome to Santiago de Compostela". Lecture directed by Dr. Cecily Hilsdale. McGill University, Montreal, QC. 8 April 2016.

Dishy, Aaron. "Digital Publics & The Radical Confrontation: Trends in Exhibition and New Media Art". Here All Alone - Symposium in New Media Art directed by Dr. Tonya Toft for The University of Copenhagen at the Kunsthal Charlottenborg, Copenhagen, Denmark. 3 June 2015.

## **CURATION**

2019 Digital Archivist and Curator for The Tailor Project at Impakt Labs, Toronto ON.

2016 Digital Archivist and Curator for Juif D'ici Digital at Federation CJA, Montreal, QC.

2015-2016 Digital Archivist and Researcher for a series of virtual exhibits at The Museum of Jewish Montreal, Montreal, QC.

2015 Co-curator for Here All Alone, an exhibition of works by digital artist Anders Weberg, directed by Dr. Tanya Toft Ag. Copenhagen, DK.

hello@aarondishy.net www.aarondishy.net 1-(514)-266-6428